

CONTACT



Mob:+91-9618586696



vaibhavchauhan638@gmail.com



Github Profile



Hyderabad, India



inkedin Profile(click here)



Personal Website (click here)

CERTIFICATIONS

•Course on Python : GOOGLE

Microsoft Certified: Azure

Fundamentals

•Microsoft SQL from A to Z-The Complete Guide to SQL Querying

Honors & Awards

Star of the Month Award

•Won Poster presentation at Marketplace - May 19

•Best Performer- Client

EDUCATION

June 2014 - May 2018

JB Institute of Engineering and Technology, Hyd-B. Tech

Academic Record:

Qualification	Percentage	Subject
STANDARD XII	87.36	Others
SSC	88	Others
BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY	67.02	C.S.E

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH Business fluent | ★★★★

हिंदी | Native | 🌣 🌣 🌣 🌣

ਪੰਜਾਬੀ | Punjabi | 🖈 🖈

<u>ತ</u>ಲುಗು | Telugu | ★★

VAIBHAV SINGH CHAUHAN

DATA ENGINEER

PROFILE

Ability to create and deliver solutions tied to Business Growth and Organizational Development

Excited to blend data and core operations across various Platforms .

Also Researching the Global economic issues and evaluating the market trends.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

Data Engineer

Hyderabad, India

Jan 2021 - Present

Exploring trends in data sets and developing algorithms to help make raw data more useful to the enterprise

Working on data retrieval optimization and communicating data trends

Linux System Administrator

Ian 2019 - December 2020

With OS specific knowledge, carrying out the design details required by Client on several flavors of Linux distributions and Windows editions. Yes, I do interact with the

Talent & Development TCS, Hyderabad

Worked in Training and development (T&D) vertical, as a SPOC for my unit and has been identified as a RIO Champion for my account.

SKILLS

***TOP SKILLS

Python Programming

Microsoft Azure

MySQL

Linux Distributions

Stock Market Analysis

Other Skills

- Artificial Intelligence (AI)
- •Data Science
- Apache Spark

Deep Learning

- Stock/Equity Research
- •NLP

- •GIT/Github
- •Big Data Analytics
- Machine learning
- •IDE-Pycharm/Atom
- •Google Colab, Jupyter notebook
- •Statistical Data Analysis
- Linux Distributions (RHEL/CentOS, Solaris, SUSElinux, Ubuntu)